Guide to the Brooklyn Dodgers collection ARC.297
Brooklyn Historical Society
Brooklyn Dodgers collection
1884-2002
1941-1957
Brooklyn Historical Society
Los Angeles Dodgers (Baseball team)
Brooklyn Dodgers (Baseball team)
ARC.297
6.75 Linear Feet in six manuscript boxes, three flat boxes, and one flat file drawer
The collection contains scorecards, programs, yearbooks, magazines, clippings, scrapbooks, posters, and other items related to the Brooklyn Dodgers, dating from 1884 to 2002, which have been collection by Brooklyn Historical Society. It also includes a small amount of items related to the Los Angeles Dodgers and pre-Brooklyn Dodgers baseball teams. Of note are several late 19th century Brooklyn baseball scorecards.
Conditions Governing Access
Audio and video cassette recordings are not currently accessible. Otherwise open to researchers without restriction.
Related Materials
Archival collections:
Eckford Social Club scrapbook, 1871-1961 (1991.049)
Larry Trapani Brooklyn Dodgers collection, 1941-1957 (2005.037)
Los Angeles Dodgers centennial press kit photographs, circa 1990 (V1991.004)
Quigley collection of Baseball memorabilia, 1943-1973 (2007.052)
Walter O'Malley Brooklyn Dodgers records, 1946-1957 (ARC.294)
William Watson Clark scrapbook, circa 1928-1938 (2011.006)
Image collections:
Brooklyn Dodgers photographs, 1949–1956 (V1987.001)
Brooklyn Dodgers Spring Training photographs (2015.023)
Brooklyn Dodgers team photographs, 1953 (V1987.019)
Chuck Connors photographs, 1938-1987 (V1987.012)
Collection of Brooklyn Dodgers photographic portraits, circa 1940-1957 (ARC.265)
Other photographs: V1973.5.1804 - V1973.5.1806; V1973.5.3678; V1974.39.44; V1982.5.20; V1984.1.639; V1987.5.1 a,b; V1987.16.1; V1987.19.1 - V1987.19.5; V1989.30.24; V1990.18.1; V1990.35.1; V1991.4.1 - V1991.4.2; V1991.52.1; V1993.10.1 - V1993.10.9
Additional photographs can be found by using the search term "Brooklyn Dodgers" in the BHS in-house image database.
Oral histories:
Ebbets Field – Dodgers Oral History, 2010
Arrangement
The collection is organized into five series:
Series 1: Official publications and scorecards
Series 2: Clippings and scrapbooks
Series 3: Memorabilia and ephemera
Series 4: Photographs and art
Series 5: Jackie Robinson Conference
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donor information has been noted on folders when available.
Donations include:
"When the Dodgers Left New York," lyrics by Tim Horrigan (Gift of Tim Horrigan, 1986)
World Series identification card, 1955, Walter O'Malley business card, and other ephemera (Gift of Irving Rudd, 1988)
Russ Meyer baseball card, 1955, and Sal Maglie baseball card, 1957 (Gift of Ellen Snyder, 1988)
Harry Lumley baseball card, 1909, and William Bergen baseball card, 1911 (Gift of Lew Lipset, circa 1988)
Score book pages, kept by Lothar Stelter, 1946 (Gift of Larry Stelter, 1992)
The Dodgers All-Time Greats - A Pictoral History - 1890-1970's and Danny Goodman - Concessions - Dodger Stadium 7" vinyl record (Gift of Lois Greene Stone, 1998)
"A World Series Remembrance: The Brooklyn Dodgers vs. The New York Yankees, 1947" lithograph by Jim Annis (Gift of Jim Annis, 2002, 2002.006)
Programs, scorecards, yearbooks, ticket stubs, audio recordings, and pennant, 1940s-1990s (Gift of Joseph P. Cogan, 2005)
1940 game diary (scrapbook), and World Series ticket stubs, 1947, 1955 (Gift of Albert Greenberg, 2005, 2005.029)
1950 program and scorecard, and 1955 Brooklyn Dodgers anniversary magazine, 1996 (Gift of Michael Colin, 2011).
Brooklyn Dodgers official cover series binder, 1988 (Gift of Peter O'Malley, 2015.002)
One copy of The Boys of Summer, by Roger Kahn, New York: Harper & Row, first edition, signed by Duke Snider, 1972; one baseball signed by Bobby Thomson and Ralph Branca, 1990s; one copy of the September 22, 1947 issue of Time magazine featuring Jackie Robinson on the cover; one copy of the September 1957 issue of Sport magazine, featuring Duke Snider on the cover, signed by Duke Snider; and sheet music for "The Brooklyn Dodgers Jump," by George T. Simon and Joe Ricardel, signed by Duke Snider, 1949 (Gift of Richard C. Atkins, 2015.032)
Two scrapbooks, 1941-1954 (Gift of Claire Lambkin, date unknown)
Line Drives from the Dodgers newsletters, 1944-1956 (Gift of Frank Michel, date unknown)
Los Angeles Dodgers yearbook, 1958 (Gift of Mrs. Kenn Stryker-Rodda, date unknown)
Scope and Contents
The collection contains scorecards, programs, yearbooks, magazines, clippings, scrapbooks, posters, and other items related to the Brooklyn Dodgers, dating from 1884 to 2002, which have been collection by Brooklyn Historical Society. It also includes a small amount of items related to the Los Angeles Dodgers and pre-Brooklyn Dodgers baseball teams. Of note are several late 19th century Brooklyn baseball scorecards.
Other Finding Aids
Item-level descriptions of photographs and artwork are available in the BHS in-house image database
Photographs; Sound recordings; Artifacts (object genre); Calendars; Printed ephemera; Newsletters; Lithographs; Baseball |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Clippings (information artifacts); Magazines (periodicals); Ephemera; Admission tickets; Baseball cards; Posters; Yearbooks; Audiocassettes; Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.); Baseball fans |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Souvenir programs; Memorabilia; Menus; African American baseball players -- New York (State) -- Kings County; Scrapbooks; Videocassettes; O'Malley, Walter, 1903-1979; Robinson, Jackie; Ebbets Field (New York, N.Y.); Snider, Duke; Long Island University; Major League Baseball (Organization); Los Angeles Dodgers (Baseball team); Brooklyn Dodgers (Baseball team)
- Series 1: Official publications and scorecards, 1884-1991
  Scope and Contents
  The series contains scorecards, programs, World Series programs, newsletters, and yearbooks, dating from 1884 to 1991. In addition to the Brooklyn Dodgers, the series include scorecards from earlier Brooklyn baseball teams, as well as some material relating to the Los Angeles Dodgers.
  - Scorecards, 1884-1946 (Box 1)
  - Program and scorecard, 1950 (Box 5)
  - Programs and scorecards, 1953-1957 (Box 1)
  - World Series programs, 1941-1955 (Box 1)
  - Newsletters, 1944-1956 (Box 1)
  - Yearbooks, 1949-1956 (Box 1)
  - Yearbooks, 1949-1957 (Box 2)
  - Los Angeles Dodgers yearbook, 1958 (Box 2)
  - Dodgers Centennial yearbooks, 1990 (Box 6)
  - Los Angeles Dodgers yearbook, 1991 (Box 6)
- Series 2: Clippings and scrapbooks, 1900-2002 (Box 4)
  The series contains magazines, scrapbooks, and clippings, dating from 1900 to 2002. Of note is one Jackie Robinson comic book, published by Fawcett Publications in 1950.
  - Gold Hours publication, "New Yorks vs. Brooklyns", 1900 (Box 6)
  - Magazines, 1929-1990 (Box 2)
  - Magazines, 1947, 1957 (Box 5)
    General
    Includes Time magazine with Jackie Robinson on the cover (September 1947) and Sport magazine with Duke Snider on the cover (signed by Snider, September 1957)
  - Jackie Robinson comic book (vol. 1 no. 4), 1950
  - The Dodgers All-Time Greats - A Pictoral History - 1890-1970's (Box 4)
  - 1955 Dodgers anniversary magazine, 1996 (Box 5)
  - Scrapbook, 1941 (Box 7)
    Assembled by Vera Novack, of 367 Rockaway Parkway
  - Scrapbooks, 1941-1954 (Box 3)
  - Scrapbook (1 of 2), 1945-1950 (Box 4)
  - Scrapbook (2 of 2), 1945-1950 (Box 5)
    Folder 26 only.
  - Clippings, 1941-2002 (Box 3)
  - Clippings (photocopies), 1947 (Box 5)
  - Clippings (oversize), 1955 (Box 6)
- Series 3: Memorabilia and ephemera, 1909-circa 2002
  The series contains assorted memorabilia and ephemera, including calendars, ticket stubs, baseball cards, postcards, audio recordings, posters, and a pennant, dating from 1909 to circa 2002. It also contains a file relating to an unrealized new stadium in Brooklyn, dating from 1981 to 1984. Of note are several early 20th century baseball cards and one copy of the first edition of The Boys of the Summer, by Roger Kahn, signed by Duke Snider.
  - The Boys of Summer, by Roger Kahn, first edition, signed by Duke Snider, 1972 (Box 5)
  - Calendars, 1990-1991 (Box 2)
  - Ticket stubs, 1941-1957 (Box 3)
  - Baseball cards, 1909-1986 (Box 3)
  - Postcards, circa 1970s (Box 3)
  - New Brooklyn stadium ephemera, 1981-1984 (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous ephemera, 1950s-1990 (Box 3)
  - "The Brooklyn Dodgers Jump" sheet music, signed by Duke Snider, 1949 (Box 5)
  - "When the Dodgers Left New York," lyrics by Tim Horrigan, 1985 (Box 5)
  - 3 audio recordings (7" and 10" vinyl records), 1949-1957 (Box 6)
  - Danny Goodman - Concessions - Dodger Stadium 7" vinyl record, 1965 (Box 4)
    "Last Inning Sandy Koufax Perfect Game - Actual Reproduction as Narrated by Vince Scully"
  - "Brooklyn Baseball Cantata" by George Merrill sleeve (photocopy), circa 2000s (Box 4)
    Photocopy of 1948 original.
  - Brooklyn Dodgers official cover series binder, 1988 (Box 6)
  - Jackie Robinson Day posters and ephemera, 1997 (Box 6)
  - Bring the Dodgers back to Brooklyn posters, 1990s (Box 6)
  - The Brooklyn Dodger menu, circa 1980s (Box 4)
  - Pennant, 1990s (Box 6)
  - Color reproduction of 1956 schedule poster, circa 2002 (Box 6)
  - 100 Years: A Visual History of the Dodgers, 1990 (Box 9)
    Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
    VHS. Run time: 1:16:00.
  - A&E Biography: Jackie Robinson, 1991 (Box 9)
    VHS. Run time: 0:50:00.
  - Here's To You, Mister Robinson, circa 1990 (Box 9)
    VHS. Run time: unknown.
  - Jackie Robinson, undated (Box 9)
  - World Series 1955 Brooklyn Dodgers Vs. New York Yankees, 1991 (Box 9)
    VHS. Run time: 0:41:00.
  - Esquire magazine Japan with cover feature on Dodgers, 1996 (Box 6)
  - Jackie Robinson Way street co-naming ceremony program and 42 patch, 2018 (Box 6)
- Series 4: Photographs and art, 1954-2002
  The series contains a 1954 photograph of Pee Wee Reese at bat versus the Chicago Cubs; a 1955 Dodgers group photograph signed by Clem Labine; and a lithograph of Ebbets Field, entitled "A World Series Remembrance: The Brooklyn Dodgers vs. The New York Yankees, 1947," produced by Jim Annis in 2002.
  - Pee Wee Reese photographs, circa 1954 (Box 6)
  - Brooklyn Dodgers team group photograph, 1955 (Box 6)
    Reproduction print signed by Clem Labine. Accessioned as V1997.065.
  - Walter O'Malley and Branch Rickey dinner photograph, 1943 (Box 6)
    Walter O'Malley and Branch Rickey pictured at a dinner table among a group of men. Taken October 1943.
  - "A World Series Remembrance: The Brooklyn Dodgers vs. The New York Yankees, 1947" lithograph by Jim Annis, 2002 (Folder Flat File)
- Series 5: Jackie Robinson Conference, 1997
  The series contains material related to the Jackie Robinson: Race, Sports and the American Dream Conference, which was held at Long Island University's Brooklyn campus in April 1997. It includes programs, press releases, brochures, and other printed ephemera, as well as 38 audio cassette tape recordings of the conference.
  - Jackie Robinson Conference audio cassette tapes and ephemera, 1997 (Box 8)